Guide to the Lawrence Laurent papers, 1948-2010 MS2325.UA
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
Lawrence Laurent papers
1948-2010
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
MS2325.UA
6.75 Linear Feet 11 standard document boxes, 1 slim document box for audio materials, and 1 flat box for oversized material
This collection contains course materials, correspondence, written reviews, speeches and lectures, programs, photographs, and audio materials from Lawrence Bell Laurent, a former Professorial Lecturer at the George Washington Univeristy. The material in this collection dates from 1948-2010, and includes records from Laurent's professional career as a radio and television critic for "The Washington Post" and his academic career teaching at American University and George Washington University. The material in the collection covers how his work influenced both his students and his peers in the field of radio and television broadcasting.
Conditions Governing Access
This collection is open for research.
Arrangement
Organized into 6 series: American University materials, George Washington University materials, Professional career, Correspondence, Photographs, and Audio materials.
Scope and Contents
This collection contains course materials, correspondence, written reviews, speeches and lectures, programs, photographs, and audio materials. The material dates from 1948-2010. These are the records of Lawrence Laurent from his professional career as a radio and television critic and from his academic career teaching at American University and George Washington University. The material in the collection covers how his work influenced both his students and his peers in the field of radio and television broadcasting.
Biographical / Historical
Lawrence Bell Laurent, a professorial lecturer for GWU, had a long career as a radio and television critic. From 1951-1982, Laurent worked as a writer for the Washington Post. After establishing himself as a respected radio critic, he soon became the first television critic for the Washington Post. During this time, he became very involved in the broadcasting industry and developed close relationships with with fellow critics, writers, directors, and actors. In 1982, Laurent retired from his job at the newspaper and began teaching broadcasting and journalism classes at several universities in the Washington, D.C. area. From 1965 to 1984, he taught several courses at American University. Then from 1984 to 2006, Laurent worked at the George Washington University as a Professorial Lecturer in both Journalism and Media and Public Affairs.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Lawrence Laurent, 2013 (2013.035).
Television criticism; Journalism
- American University course materials, 1965-1984; Series 1; 1 Linear Feet Series contains 2 standard document boxes (Box 2, Box 1)
  Arrangement
  Arranged chronologically.
  Scope and Contents
  The materials in this series include lecture notes, quizzes, exams, handouts, and other resources. The materials range in date from 1965 to 1984. These materials represent Laurent's time as a professor for American University, teaching courses including: Radio-Television Programming, Development of Broadcasting-Film, and Television Programming. The series is arranged in chronological order. Subjects include: television broadcasting, film analysis, TV news coverage and riots, TV drama, soap opera, political broadcasting, and mass communication. The series also includes the award Laurent received in 1978 from American University for Outstanding Teaching.
  - Radio-Television Programming: Lecture notes and final exam, 1965-1966 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Broadcasting and the Public Interest: Lecture notes, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Radio-TV Programming: Lecture notes, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Lecture notes and quizzes, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Lecture notes, 1969-1970 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Course materials, 1973-1980 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Development of Broadcasting - Film: Lectures I, II, III, and David Sarnoff, 1979-1982 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Development of Broadcasting: Lectures IV, V, VI, 1979-1982 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Development of Broadcasting - Film: Lectures VII, VIII, and IX, 1979-1982 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Development of Broadcasting - Film: Lectures XI and XII, 1979-1982 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Development: "The 1950s" - 11th, 12th, 13th lectures, 1979-1982 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Lectures: "The Consumer Movement," "Summing Up," and "The Future", 1979-1982 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Development of Broadcasting - Film: Lecture notes, quizzes, and exams, 1979-1982 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - "Broadcasting: The 50th Anniversary Issue" - course resource, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - TV Drama, c 1979-1982 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - A Summation, c 1979-1982 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Development of Broadcasting - Film: First Lecture, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Development of Broadcasting - Film: 2nd Lecture, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Development of Broadcasting - Film: 3rd Lecture, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Development of Broadcasting - Film: 4th Lecture, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Development of Broadcasting - Film: 5th Lecture, 1982 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Development of Broadcasting - Film: 6th Lecture, 1982 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Development of Broadcasting - Film: 7th Lecture, 1982 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Development of Broadcasting - Film: 8th Lecture, 1982 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Development of Broadcasting - Film: 9th Lecture, 1982 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Development of Broadcasting - Film: 10th Lecture, 1982 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Development of Broadcasting - Film: 11th Lecture, 1982 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Development of Broadcasting - Film: 12th Lecture, 1982 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Development of Broadcasting - Film: 13th Lecture, 1982 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Television Programming: Lectures, 1982-1984 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Television Programming: Bill Moyers, 1982-1984 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Television Programming 17.588: Second Lecture - "Innes, McLuhan and Laurent", 1984 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Television Programming: 7th Lecture, 1984 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Television Programming: 9th Lecture, 1984 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Television Programming: 11th Lecture, 1984 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Television Programming: 12th Lecture - Soap Opera, 1984 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - American University Award for Outstanding Teaching, 1978 (Box 2, Folder 17)
- George Washington University course materials, 1984-2005; Series 2; 2 Linear Feet Series contains 4 standard document boxes (Box 3, Box 4, Box 5, Box 6)
  The materials in this series include lecture notes, quizzes, exams, assignments, handouts, guest lectures, and other resources. The materials range in date from 1984 to 2010. These materials represent Laurent's time as a professor for George Washington University, teaching courses such as Critical Writing and Reviewing. The series is arranged in chronological order. Subjects include: critics and criticism, sitcom history, politics and TV, internet, headlines, poetry, and situational press ethics.
  - Mystery of Talent, 1984-2004 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Dominant Entertainment Medium, 1984-2005 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Critics and Criticism, 1986-1992 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Ideas and Trends, 1990 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - The INTV Journal - Sitcom History, 1990 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Joe Gonzales - Monroe, LA, 1990-1992 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - A Summing Up [1 of 2], 1990-2004 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - A Summing Up [2 of 2], 1990-2004 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Politics and TV, 1991 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Frederick Jackson Turner: The Significance of the Frontier, 1991-1998 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Larry Gelbart on Writing, 1991-1997 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Los Angeles: Marvin Hamlisch, 1992 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - The Bible: Eloquence, 1992-2000 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Boorstin: "The Discoverers", 1992-2000 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Commonly Confused Words, 1992-2000 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Crickets, Carson, Behan, 1992-2000 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Daniel Bell, 1992-2000 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Dante's System of Hell, 1992-2000 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Few and Far Between, 1992-2000 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Government Agency Securities, 1992-2000 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Grammar and Linguistic Terms, 1992-2000 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Howard Beale: "Network", 1992-2000 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - "Muck-Raker", 1992-2000 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Paul Johnson: "Modern Times", 1992-2000 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Professor Daniel Bell's Views on Why Religion has Survived, 1992-2000 (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Professor Willson's Insurance Funny Fillings, 1992-2000 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - Robert Penn Warren, 1992-2000 (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - "The Sage of the Fountain Inn", 1992-2000 (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - To "the good ole' days", 1992-2000 (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - Writing Poetry, 1992-2000 (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - Wanted: The Complete Television Critic, 1992-2000 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - On Writing, 1992-2003 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Stress Is..., 1992-2005 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - George Washington University - Assignments, 1992-2005 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - George Washington University - Handouts, 1992-2005 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Grantland Rice, 1993 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Richard Lederer - Student Bloopers, 1994 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - 'The New Yorker' articles, 1994-1997 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Deconstructive Criticism, 1994-1999 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Visuals - Comics/Cartoons, 1994-2001 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Lectures 3 and 4: The Mystery of Talent [1 of 2], 1994-2005 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Lectures 3 and 4: The Mystery of Talent [2 of 2], 1994-2005 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - "A Gentle Madness" - Institutions, 1995 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Guest Lecturers, 1995-2003 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Breaking the Rules, 1996 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Footnotes, 1996 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Gerry Spence, 1996 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - "How Do You Spell Quality?", 1996 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Barbara Tuchman's Writing of King James Bible, 1996-1997 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - "How to Curry Favor with the Critics", 1996-1997 (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - John Daly Quote, 1996-2000 (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - "A Cheat Sheet for Capitol Newcomers", 1997 (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Class Lecture - April 29, 1997 (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - Criticism Lecture, 1997 (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - Dangerous Reading in Its Day, 1997 (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - Ethics, 1997 (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - Feeding the Couch Potatoes, 1997 (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - Film: "Midnight in the Garden of Good and Evil", 1997 (Box 4, Folder 28)
  - Internet and Headlines, 1997 (Box 4, Folder 29)
  - Lapham: "The Consolations of Vanity", 1997 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Sounding Off on Language, 1997 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Poetry Lecture, 1997-1999 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Faulkner, 1997-2002 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - "As Others See Us", 1997-2004 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Survey Stats - Tainted Truth, 1997-2004 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - George Washington University - Introduction, 1997-2005 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - George Washington University - Quizzes, 1997-2005 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - The Entertainment Glut, 1998 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - The Experts Speak, 1998 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Skeptics and Critics, 1998-2000 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Old and New Forms of Entertainment, 1998-2001 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - The Entertainment Economy, 1999 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Henry Louis Mencken, 1999 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - J.J. Kilpatrick, Quiz I and II, 1999 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Loren Eiseley, 1999 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Noisome, 1999 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Developing Your Own Style [1 of 2], 1999-2000 (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Developing Your Own Style [2 of 2], 1999-2000 (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Situational Press Ethics, 1999-2004 (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Josh Logan - The Transistor, 2000 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Names Lecture, 2000 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Keynes, 2000-2002 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Liberal and Conservative Words, 2000-2003 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Pauline Kael, 2000-2003 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - First Session, 2000-2005 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - George Bernard Shaw, 2000-2005 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Writing - Philosophy Writers, 2000-2005 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Why Critics?, 2001 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - George Washington University - Lectures I, 2002 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - George Washington University - Lectures II, 2002 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Truman and Hume, 2002 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Stolen Words, 2002-2005 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - The Monopolist, 2003 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - "A Young Nation's Growth Spurt", 2003 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - One More Time - Copyright, 2003-2004 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Critics and Dirty Tricks, 2004 (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - The Psychiatrist Critic, 2004 (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - Classic Critical Terminology, 2004-2005 (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - Dorothy Parker, 2005 (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - George Washington University Syllabus - Journalism 135, 2005 (Box 6, Folder 21)
- Professional materials, 1948-2008; Series 3; 2.5 Linear Feet Series is split between 3 standard document boxes and 1 flat box for oversize materials (Box 7, Box 8, Box 9, Box 12)
  Organized into 3 subseries (1. Written Works by, about, or Reviewed by Laurent, 2. Public Lectures and Speeches, and 3. Miscellaneous Event Invitations, Conference Materials, and Honors). Arranged chronologically within the subseries.
  The materials in this series include radio and television reviews, drafts, public lectures and speeches, invitations, conference materials, and other resources and notes. The materials range in date from 1948 to 2008. These materials represent Laurent's professional career as a radio and television critic. The series is arranged into 3 subseries: 1) Written works by, about, or reviewed by Laurent, 2) Public lectures and speeches, and 3) Event invitations, conference materials, notes, and honors. The materials within the subseries are arranged chronologically.
  - Written works by, about, or reviewed by Laurent, 1948-1998; MS2325.UA Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 7, Box 8)
    Subseries: Arranged chronologically.
    Items of interest within subseries 1 include articles from: the University of Virginia's 'The Cavalier Daily' (1948-1959), 'TV Guide,' 'Television Quarterly,' 'Radio Television Daily,' 'The Washington Post,' and 'INTV Journal.' There are also drafts of works by Lawrence Laurent, Buddy Ebsen, Erik Barnouw, Manny Lucoff, and Richard Laurent.
    - The Cavalier Daily, 1948-1959 (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - Miscellaneous Works by Laurent, 1956-1971 (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - Miscellaneous Works about Laurent, 1958-1986 (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - Reviews by Lawrence Laurent, 1968-2002 (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - Erik Barnouw's "History of Broadcasting", 1970 (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - "A TV Year of Social Critique", 1971 (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - "Leroy Collins and the National Association of Broadcasters: Experiment in the Public Interest" by Manny Lucoff, 1971 (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - "The Champagne General" by Christian ("Buddy") Ebsen, 1973 (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Erik Barnouw's Draft of "The Sponsor", 1977 (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - "Sea Pines Adventure" by Lawrence Laurent, 1984 (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Laurent's INTV Daily Journal, 1991 (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - INTV Journal Works by Laurent, 1991-1995 (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - "Resultados En Las Lenguas Romances De Adjectivos Con Desinencias Derivadas De - TUM" by Richard Laurent, 1998 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Public lectures and speeches, 1959-1991; MS2325.UA Series 3 Subseries 2 (Box 9)
    Items of interest within subseries 2 include lectures and speeches for: the American University convocation, the Phi Beta Kappa Association monthly meeting, the Washington Film Council, the Institute for Education by Radio-Television, the American Women in Radio and Television, the National Association of Television Program Executives, the Virginia Association of Broadcsters, The Washington Post summer interns, and the National Press Club.
    - Laurent Public Lectures and Speeches [1 of 9], 1959 (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - Laurent Public Lectures and Speeches [2 of 9], 1962-1963 (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - Laurent Public Lectures and Speeches [3 of 9], 1964 (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - Laurent Public Lectures and Speeches [4 of 9], 1965 (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - Laurent Public Lectures and Speeches [5 of 9], 1966-1967 (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - Laurent Public Lectures and Speeches [6 of 9], 1968 (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - Laurent Public Lectures and Speeches [7 of 9], 1984 (Box 9, Folder 7)
    - Laurent Public Lectures and Speeches [8 of 9], 1990-1991 (Box 9, Folder 8)
    - Laurent Public Lectures and Speeches [9 of 9], undated (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Event invitations, conference materials, notes, and honors, 1959-2008; MS2325.UA Series 3 Subseries 3 (Box 12, Box 9)
    Items of interest within subseries 3 include: invitations and programs for events, miscellaneous notes and resources, Laurent's award from Syracuse University for being a guest lecturer of television (1965), Laurent's notebook from the Airlie Seminar on the Art of Radio, and Laurent's ordination certificate from the Universal Life Church (1997).
    - Invitations and Events, 1959-2003 (Box 9, Folder 10)
    - Resources, 1959-2010 (Box 9, Folder 11)
    - TV Guide: Vol. 12, No. 36, 1964 (Box 9, Folder 12)
    - Award from Syracuse University, 1965 (Box 9, Folder 13)
    - Airlie Seminar on the Art of Radio, circa 1977-1983 (Box 9, Folder 14)
    - Notes, 1990-1994 (Box 9, Folder 15)
    - Universal Life Church Ordination Certification, 1997 (Box 9, Folder 16)
    - National Association of Broadcasters: Legal Guide to FCC Broadcast Rules, Regulations and Policies, 1977 (Box 12, Folder 1)
- Correspondence, 1948-2010; Series 4; 1 Linear Feet Series contains 2 standard document boxes (Box 10, Box 11)
  The materials in this series include written and typed correspondence to and from Lawrence Laurent. The materials range in date from 1948 to 2010. These materials represent Laurent's personal life and professional career as a radio and television critic. The series is arranged in chronological order. Series includes correspondence with the following individuals: Buddy Ebsen, Betty White, Ed Sullivan, Dick Clark, James Stewart, Jack Webb, Drew Pearson, Gypsy Rose Lee, Spike Jones, Red Skelton, Ezra Stone, Tom Tully, Herb Shriner, Danny Thomas, George Gobel, Barbara Walters, Jack Lord, Shelley Berman, Connie B. Gay, Lois F. Stark, Rod Serling, Dan O'Brien, and Congressman Richard Ray. The series also includes letters from 'The Washington Post,' 'Television Quarterly,' CBS Television, the National Broadcasting Company, Inc., the Democratic National Committee, and various universities.
  - Correspondence, 1948-1955 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, 1956-1957 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, 1958-1959 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, 1960-1961 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, 1962-1963 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, 1964-1969 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, 1970-1979 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence, 1982-1989 (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence, 1990-1991 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, 1992-2010 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, undated (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence - Bill Clinton and Democratic National Committee, 1994-1999 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence - Democratic National Committee, 1995-2001 (Box 11, Folder 5)
- Photographs, 1955-1994; Series 5; 1.5 Linear Feet Series is split between 1 standard document box and 1 flat box for oversize materials (Box 12, Box 11)
  The materials in this series include photographs of or for Lawrence Laurent. The materials range in date from 1955 to 2003. These materials represent Laurent's personal life and professional career as a radio and television critic. The series is arranged in chronological order. Series includes photographs of Laurent with: Rocky Marciano, Bob Pickett, John Neville, Shelley Berman, Dan O'Brien, Andrew Stevens, Jacky Benny, and George Washington University faculty and students. Series also includes autographed photographs from: George Gobel, Pat Brown, Buddy Ebsen, Jack Lord, Tom Tully, and Danny Thomas.
  - Autographed photo of actor George Gobel, 1955 (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Laurent with boxer Rocky Marciano and others at Goldie Ahearn's Restaurant, 1955 (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Laurent with Bob Pickett at the Purple Tree Lounge, 1957 (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Laurent at the Golden Parrot Restaurant with Mayor Yates and others, 1957 (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - Laurent at Olmsted's Restaurant with actor John Neville and other journalists, 1959 (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - Lawrence Laurent with son, Richard, 1962 (Box 11, Folder 12)
  - Larry Laurent and Shelley Berman, 1963 (Box 11, Folder 13)
  - Letter and photo from Tom O.W. Riegel, 1964 (Box 11, Folder 14)
  - TV Stations, Inc. Management Seminar, 1968 (Box 11, Folder 15)
  - 20 Year Club New Members, 1970 (Box 11, Folder 16)
  - Autographed photo and postcard from Pat Brown, 1977, 1984 (Box 11, Folder 17)
  - Laurent on the back lot of Universal Studios during the filming of "The Bastard", 1978 (Box 11, Folder 18)
  - Photos from actor Buddy Ebsen, 1978-2003 (Box 11, Folder 19)
  - Photo correspondence from actor Gene Reynolds, 1982 (Box 11, Folder 20)
  - GWU class "Critical Writing" party at home of Professor Laurent, 25 April 1992 (Box 11, Folder 21)
  - George Washington University 1993 (Box 11, Folder 22)
  - George Washington University 1994 (Box 11, Folder 23)
  - Autographed photo from Jack Lord, undated (Box 11, Folder 24)
  - Laurent at National Press Club, Washington, undated (Box 11, Folder 25)
  - Miscellaneous Meetings, Conferences, and Events, undated (Box 11, Folder 26)
  - Signed photo from actor Tom Tully, undated (Box 11, Folder 27)
  - Autographed photo of actor Danny Thomas, 1958 (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Jacky Benny and Larry Laurent, 1965 (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Filtered print of Larry Laurent, undated (Box 12, Folder 4)
- Audio materials, 1948-2005; Series 6; 0.25 Linear Feet Series contains 1 slim document box (Box 13)
  The materials in this series include: a vinyl recording of Laurent on CBS (1948), 11 audio cassette tapes of lectures on television broadcasting (c. 1977) and a corresponding letter from Dan O'Brien. The materials range in date from 1948 to 2005. These materials represent Laurent's profesional career as a radio-TV critic and a professor. The series is arranged in chronological order, with the exception of the letter which was placed before the corresponding cassette tapes.
  - Audio Recording of Larry Laurent on CBS, 1948; Contains 1 LP record (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Letter from Dan O'Brien about Audio Cassette Tapes, 2005 (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Recorded Lectures on Television Broadcasting (Tapes 1-4), circa 1977; Contains 4 audio cassette tapes (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Recorded Lectures on Television Broadcasting (Tapes 5-8), circa 1977; Contains 4 audio cassette tapes (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - Recorded Lectures on Television Broadcasting (Tapes 9-11), circa 1977; Contains 3 audio cassette tapes (Box 13, Folder 5)